[{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"J","question":"1. During a conversation in this novel, a man admits he would “eat anything from an animal, the last remains,” but he finds a “plain, raw carrot… quite distasteful.” At the end of this novel, the protagonist tells the Japanese Ministry of Transport in Mexico an alternative story about a cannibal cook. After discovering fruit that contains human teeth, the protagonist of this novel leaves an island full of meerkats. The protagonist of this novel, who simultaneously practices Hinduism, Islam, and Christianity, survives a shipwreck with Richard Parker. For 10 points, name this novel by Yann Martel (“YAWN mar-TEL”) about Piscine Patel, who is stranded on a lifeboat for 227 days with a Bengal tiger. ","answer":"ANSWER: Life of Pi <World/Other Literature> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"J","question":"2. Molecules with this property can dimerize into parallel-displaced and T-shaped conformations, which are examples of stacking interactions. The Birch reduction removes this property from molecules. Tryptophan, histidine, phenylalanine, and tyrosine all exhibit this property. Molecules with this property have four n plus two pi electrons, exhibit a planar geometry, and must be cyclical according to Hückel’s rule. A snake devouring its tail inspired August Kekulé (“KAY-koo-lay”) to propose the shape of a molecule with this property. For 10 points, name this molecular property that is responsible for stabilizing benzene and has a good-smelling name. ","answer":"ANSWER: aromaticity [or aromatic; prompt on resonance] <Chemistry> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"J","question":"3. A senator from this state earlier served as Secretary of the Treasury under his father-in-law Woodrow Wilson. William Gibbs McAdoo (“MACK-uh-doo”) represented this state, which Wilson narrowly won in 1916 partly because Charles Evans Hughes received little help from its progressive governor Hiram Johnson. In 1934, a governor’s race in this state was lost by Upton Sinclair, whose EPIC campaign sought to “end poverty in” this state. Japanese internment was supported by a governor of this state, Earl Warren, who later opposed another politician from this state who became Dwight Eisenhower’s vice president. For 10 points, Richard Nixon hailed from what West Coast state? ","answer":"ANSWER: California <American History> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"J","question":"4. In an opera centered on a man with this profession, a lullaby in which a “cloud-flower blossoms” is sung by that man’s Tewa (“TAY-wah”) housemaid. A 2005 libretto by Peter Sellars has a man with this job sing “Batter My Heart, Three- Personed God,” and elsewhere quotes the Bhagavad Gita. Performances of “I Feel the Earth Move” and “Mr. Bojangles” appear in an opera titled for a man with this job that opens the composer’s Portrait Trilogy. In that opera, the title member of this profession plays violin in one of five plotless “knee plays.” For 10 points, name this profession of the title characters of both John Adams’s Dr. Atomic and Philip Glass’s Einstein on the Beach. ","answer":"ANSWER: scientists [accept physicists; accept Dr. Atomic until read, but prompt on doctor by asking “he has a doctorate in what field?”; prompt on descriptions like people on the Manhattan Project] <Other Arts> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"J","question":"5. A symbolic form of this practice that acts to maintain a dominant culture’s hegemony was identified in Pierre Bourdieu’s Distinction. Marshall Sahlins resigned from the National Academy of Sciences on account of a book which alleged that the Yanomami constantly engaged in this behavior. Patrick Tierney’s Darkness at El Dorado suggests that Napoleon Chagnon (“SHAG-nun”) encouraged that Amazonian tribe to engage in this practice. The narrative that this practice’s frequency has declined over time appears in The Better Angels of Our Nature by Steven Pinker. Max Weber (“VAY-bur”) said that the state has a legitimate monopoly on the use of this phenomenon. For 10 points, identity this behavior often defined as “the intentional use of force.” ","answer":"ANSWER: violence [accept force until read; accept war] <Social Science> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"J","question":"6. This empire’s judicial system was administered by a general assembly called the Pankus that enforced a remarkably non-violent legal code. The Kingdom of Mitanni was conquered by this empire’s ruler Suppiluliuma I (“SUP-il-oo-lee-OO-mah the first”), but this empire lost control of it after losing the Battle of Nihriya to Assyria. Another ruler of this empire, Muwatalli II (“moo-wa-TA-lee the second”), moved its capital south from Hattusa and clashed with a rival civilization near the Orontes River in 1274 BC. At that chariot battle, this empire clashed with Ramesses II’s Egyptians by the town of Kadesh. For 10 points, name this ancient Anatolian civilization. ","answer":"ANSWER: Hittites [or Hittite empire; or Hittite civilization] <World History> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"J","question":"7. A system named for this behavior was proposed by Balthasar Van der Pol. The Morse potential accounts for deviations from this behavior. Atoms in Einstein’s heat capacity model were treated as displaying this behavior. Another system named for this behavior has wavefunction solutions equal to the product of a Gaussian and an Hermite (“air-MEET”) polynomial. Motion of this type may be eliminated using critical damping. In a simple system exhibiting this behavior, the restoring force is proportional to displacement. For 10 points, Hooke’s law describes what type of motion exhibited by masses on springs and pendulums? ","answer":"ANSWER: oscillation [or word forms such as oscillatory motion or behavior; accept simple harmonic oscillator or SHO; accept simple harmonic motion or SHM; accept quantum harmonic oscillator or QHO; accept quantum harmonic motion or QHM; accept Van der Pol oscillator] <Physics> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"J","question":"8. While he isn’t the same-named inventor of the sewing machine, Isaac Singer invented a controversial machine for the rapid production of this substance. Ultra-Orthodox groups insist on the shmurah form of this substance, which is diligently guarded throughout its creation. Three pieces of this substance sit [emphasize] next to a plate of six symbolic foods, and customarily, children attempt to find a hidden portion of this substance called the afikoman (“ah-fee-KO-min”). This substance acts as a substitute for chametz (“kha-METS”), whose consumption is not permitted on Passover. Traditionally, this flour-based food isn’t allowed to rise, in tribute to the hasty nature of the Exodus. For 10 points, name this type of unleavened bread central to many Jewish rituals. ","answer":"ANSWER: matzo [or matzah; or matzot; or matzos; prompt on bread or unleavened bread until read; prompt on dough] <Religion> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"J","question":"9. An anonymous book that was [emphasize] misattributed to this author argued that God’s command to exterminate the Canaanites was illegitimate because “All Revelation” must fall within the bounds of moral law. That book was actually written by his follower Johann Gottlieb Fichte (“FICK-tuh”). This philosopher held that space and time are not “empirical concepts” but instead “forms of intuition.” This thinker divided a “thing-in-itself” from one’s perception of it, or the noumenon (“NOO-muh-non”) from the phenomenon. This thinker found that some nonanalytic facts could still be known a priori, such as that “seven plus five equals twelve.” For 10 points, name this German whose three critiques include the Critique of Pure Reason. ","answer":"ANSWER: Immanuel Kant (The first two lines describe Johann Gottlieb Fichte’s Attempt at a Critique of All Revelation) <Philosophy> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"J","question":"0. This author did not complete a historical romance whose title “Moor” was based on the life of his great-grandfather Abram Gannibal. This author, who was exiled for reciting his controversial “Ode to Liberty,” created a protagonist who rejects a woman’s love letter in a namesake “sermon” and is the original model for the archetype of the superfluous man. This author used an iambic tetrameter verse form that alternates between masculine and feminine rhymes for a novel about a man who loves Tatyana and kills Lensky in a duel. For 10 points, name this Russian poet of Eugene Onegin. ","answer":"ANSWER: Alexander Pushkin [or Alexander Sergeyevich Pushkin] <European Literature> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"J","question":"1. A man wearing Timberland boots and camouflage stands in for this person in a painting by Kehinde (“keh-HIN-day”) Wiley. A painting of this man inspired a more realistic rendition completed by Paul Delaroche. A man wears a hat with the number 32 in a painting in which this man heals some plague victims by Antoine-Jean Gros (“groh”). Rocks with the names of Charlemagne, Hannibal, and this man appear in the lower left of an idealized portrait in which he sports a billowing red cloak and points towards the St. Bernard Pass while on a rearing horse. For 10 points, name this leader whom Jacques-Louis David painted “crossing the Alps.” ","answer":"ANSWER: Napoleon I [or Napoleon Bonaparte; do not accept or prompt on “Napoleon III”] <Painting/Sculpture> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"J","question":"2. In World War I–era Germany, Jewish doctor Nathan Zuntz’s unsuccessful plan to save food by killing these animals exacerbated both famine and anti-Semitism. In 266 BC, Megara broke an Antigonid siege by releasing a flaming horde of these animals toward the Macedonian war elephants. Via the PEPPADEP program, Haiti killed nearly its entire population of these farm animals, whose back bristles were used to make the first toothbrushes in ancient China. Historically, outhouses were often linked to pits of these farm animals, as they are known for their ability to eat anything. For 10 points, which mammals provided their name to a devastating 2009 H1N1 outbreak? ","answer":"ANSWER: pigs [accept swine, hogs, sows, or boars; accept war pigs; accept Creole pigs] (The lead-in refers to the Schweinemord.) <European History> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"J","question":"3. This mathematician discovered that [read slowly] if a number is 4 more than a multiple of 5, then the number of its partitions is a multiple of 5; that was one of his namesake “congruences.” In 1976, George Andrews rediscovered this man’s “lost notebook,” which contained much of his work on mock theta functions. He legendarily recognized that the number 1729 is the smallest number that can be expressed as the sum of two cubes in two different ways, leading to the term “taxicab numbers.” That story was recounted by G. H. Hardy, who mentored this mathematician despite his lack of formal training. For 10 points, name this Indian mathematician. ","answer":"ANSWER: Srinivasa Ramanujan <Other Science> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"J","question":"4. This character is “the Shaker God incarnated” according to a man who believes himself to be the archangel Gabriel. This character becomes a prophecy’s first hearse during three chapters titled “The Chase.” This is the main character discussed during a novel’s nine “gams,” or meetings. As a reward for the first person to see this character, a man offers a gold doubloon that he nails to a mast. Before accidentally killing himself, that man tells this character “From Hell’s heart, I stab at thee!” The protagonist uses Queequeg’s coffin as a lifeboat after this character destroys the Pequod. For 10 points, name this giant whale pursued by Captain Ahab in a novel by Herman Melville. ","answer":"ANSWER: Moby Dick [prompt on the whale or the white whale until read] <American Literature> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"J","question":"9. Larry Vance argued that Zaharie Ahmad Shah’s suicide caused one of these objects to disappear. A series of disasters in Malaysia and Ethiopia involved the anti-stalling system of the Dreamliner model of these objects. For 10 points, a lost Lockheed Model 10-E Electra is an example of what class of vehicles, a missing example of which was flown by Amelia Earhart? ","answer":"ANSWER: airplanes [or aeroplanes; accept synonyms such as jets, aircraft, or airliners; accept specific models of planes such as passenger planes, clippers, or a seaplane] <CE/Geo/Other/Pop Culture> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"J","question":"6. Locations such as Gargas and Rouffignac (“roo-feen-YAHK”) are home to a variety of these things often produced using “moonmilk,” and are known as “flutings.” The creation of one of these things at Namibia’s Brandberg Mountain was incorrectly attributed to Mediterranean travellers by Henri Breuil (“broy”), who attributed their production to early beliefs in magic. A group of French boys searching for a lost dog first discovered many of these things at a complex that includes the Hall of the Bulls. Paleolithic individuals produced these things at Lascaux (“lah-SKOH”) by applying ochre, hematite, charcoal, and other pigments to walls. For 10 points, name this type of prehistoric art found in subterranean locations. ","answer":"ANSWER: cave paintings [accept cave art, cave drawings, painted cave, or other descriptive answers of art located within a cave; accept petroglyphs; prompt on paintings, drawings, or art by asking “located where?”; prompt on wall paintings; prompt on rock paintings] <European History> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"J","question":"7. John Taplow gifts his schoolmaster Arthur Crocker-Harris this author’s translation of Agamemnon in a play by Terence Rattigan. A poem by this author concludes with the couplet “And all night long we have not stirred, / And yet God has not said a word!” In that poem by this author, the narrator muses “I am quite sure she felt no pain” after strangling his lover with her yellow hair. Another poem by this author describes a “gift of a nine-hundred-years-old name” to a woman with a “heart… too soon made glad” whose portrait was painted by Fra Pandolf. For 10 points, name this Victorian poet of “Porphyria’s Lover” and “My Last Duchess.” ","answer":"ANSWER: Robert Browning [prompt on Browning] <British Literature> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"J","question":"8. The enzyme TPH1 (“T-P-H-one”) produces this compound in mast cells and leukocytes. The protein encoded by 5-HTT is a transporter for this molecule, which has its release regulated in enterochromaffin cells and raphe (“RAY-fee”) nuclei. Psilocin and lysergic acid diethylamide bind to receptors for this molecule. MAOs convert this molecule to 5-hydroxy·indole·acetic acid. Prozac and Zoloft are medications that increase extracellular levels of this molecule; those antidepressants are selective “reuptake inhibitors” of this molecule. Appetite and sleep are regulated by, for 10 points, what neurotransmitter that affects mood? ","answer":"ANSWER: serotonin [or 5-HT or 5-hydroxytryptamine] <Biology> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"J","question":"9. The characteristic finale of a symphony by this composer moves through five other sections before an epilogue inspired by the novel Tono-Bungay. The finale of a symphony by this composer is the 30-minute-long movement “The Explorers,” which follows a chorus’s depiction of ocean waves. His second symphony contains quotations of the Westminster Chimes, while his first sets such Walt Whitman poems as “After the Sea-Ship.” This composer based another piece on an earlier composer’s “Why Fum’th (“FYOO-mith”) in Fight.” He wrote A Sea Symphony, A London Symphony, and Fantasia on Greensleeves. For 10 points, name this composer of Fantasia on a Theme by Thomas Tallis and The Lark Ascending. ","answer":"ANSWER: Ralph (“rafe”) Vaughan Williams [prompt on Williams] <Classical Music> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"J","question":"0. In an Egyptian myth, a sailor shipwrecked on an island speaks to one of these animals, which calls itself the Lord of Punt. During the New Kingdom, priests mutilated wax figures of these animals in a popular execration ritual. One of these animals is depicted in the uraeus symbol, which is sacred to the goddess Wadjet. Isis creates one of these animals out of sand wet by Ra’s spittle. One of these animals has to be defeated each night for Ra to safely pass through the Duat. That one of these animals represents chaos and is named Apep or Apophis. For 10 points, Cleopatra killed herself with a bite from what venomous animal? ","answer":"ANSWER: serpents [or snakes or vipers; accept cobras or asps] <Mythology> Bonuses "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"J","question":"[10] Name this 20th-century social movement that sought to promote cultural and economic empowerment among Mexican Americans. ","answer":"ANSWER: Chicano movement [or Chicana movement; or Chicanx movement; or Xicano movement; or Xicana movement; or Xicanx movement] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"J","question":"[10] The Chicano blowouts were concentrated in this southern California city. During World War II, Hispanic residents of this city were targeted in the Zoot Suit Riots. ","answer":"ANSWER: Los Angeles [or LA] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"J","question":"[10] This Chicana activist worked with César Chavez to cofound the United Farm Workers. She coined the UFW’s slogan, “Sí se puede” (“see say PWEH-day”). ","answer":"ANSWER: Dolores Huerta <American History> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"J","question":"[10] Name this artist. This pioneer of Dadaism is best known for his readymades, including Fountain, a urinal signed with the name R. Mutt. ","answer":"ANSWER: Marcel Duchamp "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"J","question":"[10] Duchamp showed his painting Nude Descending a Staircase, No. 2 at this 1913 exhibition. This New York exhibition was organized by Walt Kuhn and Arthur B. Davies. ","answer":"ANSWER: the Armory Show [or the International Exhibition of Modern Art] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"J","question":"[10] A work whose title asks this woman “Why not sneeze?” is a birdcage filled with marble blocks that look like sugar cubes. This female alter-ego of Marcel Duchamp has a name punning on the French for “Eros, such is life.” ","answer":"ANSWER: Rrose Sélavy (“AIR-rose say-lah-VEE”) [or Rose Sélavy; accept Why Not Sneeze, Rose Sélavy?] <Painting/Sculpture> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"J","question":"[10] Name this character who owns a poetry-covered baseball mitt. This character’s siblings include Phoebe, D.B., and Holden. ","answer":"ANSWER: Allie Caulfield [or Kenneth Caulfield; prompt on Caulfield or Holden Caulfield’s younger brother] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"J","question":"[10] Allie Caulfield’s brother Holden spends much of this J. D. Salinger novel wandering around New York City after his expulsion from Pencey Prep. ","answer":"ANSWER: The Catcher in the Rye "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"J","question":"[10] Another Caulfield named Curtis is briefly mentioned in An Introduction to this other character. In a short story, this husband of Muriel kisses the arch of a young girl’s foot while at the beach. ","answer":"ANSWER: Seymour Glass [prompt on Glass] (That story is “A Perfect Day for Bananafish.”) <American Literature> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"J","question":"[10] This organ is susceptible to neovascularization, which can lead to edema (“uh-DEE-muh”). Anti-VEGF (“anti-vej-F”) treatments used to treat afflictions of this organ include aflibercept and ranibizumab, and a microkeratome can be used for surgery on this organ. ","answer":"ANSWER: eyes "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"J","question":"[10] Neovascularization can cause this disease of the eye. Its most common type is open-angle, and it is caused by increased pressure in the eye. ","answer":"ANSWER: glaucoma "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"J","question":"[10] Eyes are extensively studied in this model organism, an insect in the genus Drosophila. Thomas Hunt Morgan used its white-eye mutant to study the inheritance of sex-linked traits. ","answer":"ANSWER: common fruit fly [or vinegar fly; accept Drosophila melanogaster; prompt on Drosophila] <Biology> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"J","question":"[10] Name these two characters. Like their father and uncle, they are summoned to the underworld because the noise of their ball game angered the lords of Xibalba (“shee-BALL-buh”). ","answer":"ANSWER: Mayan Hero Twins [or Hunahpu and Xbalanque in either order; prompt on twins] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"J","question":"[10] The Hero Twins were conceived when their mother’s hand was wet by a calabash that used to be one of these body parts. The Olmecs created colossal sculptures of these body parts. ","answer":"ANSWER: heads [accept skulls] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"J","question":"[10] The lords of Xibalba play the ball game using the head of Hunahpu as the ball after he is decapitated in the house of these animals. The god Camazotz takes the form of one of these animals. ","answer":"ANSWER: bats <Mythology> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"J","question":"[10] Name these objects whose gravitational fields are so strong that not even light can escape them. ","answer":"ANSWER: black holes [accept supermassive black holes] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"J","question":"[10] For a non-rotating black hole, the radius of the event horizon is named for this German physicist. ","answer":"ANSWER: Karl Schwarzschild (“SHWARTZ-shilled”) "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"J","question":"[10] Schwarzschild also names a metric that represents a solution to these equations. These equations include a constant term equal to 8 pi times big G divided by the speed of light to the fourth power. ","answer":"ANSWER: Einstein field equations [or EFE; accept Einstein’s equations] <Other Science> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"J","question":"[10] Name this letter, whose author spent a year in England to escape libel charges after writing it. This letter, which primarily attributes blame to the “extraordinary imaginations” of Major du Paty de Clam, was first published in the newspaper L’Aurore (“lo-ROR”). ","answer":"ANSWER: “J’Accuse” [10] Émile Zola wrote “J’Accuse” as a protest against the jailing of this Frenchman, whose namesake affair reflected contemporary French antisemitism. "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"J","question":"[10] During his period of incarceration, Dreyfus spent a couple of years on Devil’s Island, which was just off the coast of this French overseas possession in South America. ","answer":"ANSWER: French Guiana [do not accept or prompt on “British Guiana,” “Dutch Guiana,” or “Suriname”; do not accept or prompt on “Guyana”; prompt on Guyane (“gwee-YAHN”)] <European History> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"J","question":"[10] A woman named Blue returns to Oakland in Tommy Orange’s novel There, There, which is titled for this author’s own description of Oakland. This author of The Autobiography of Alice B. Toklas wrote “Rose is a rose is a rose is a rose.” ","answer":"ANSWER: Gertrude Stein "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"J","question":"[10] This author wrote a novel whose narrators include the color red, a miniaturist named Black, and the murdered Elegant Effendi. ","answer":"ANSWER: Orhan Pamuk [or Ferit Orhan Pamuk] (The novel is My Name Is Red.) "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"J","question":"[10] Lady Murasaki, whose name means “violet,” may have included herself as a love interest of the title character in this Heian (“HAY-on”)-era novel about a “Shining Prince.” ","answer":"ANSWER: The Tale of Genji [or Genji monogatari] <World/Other Literature> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"J","question":"[10] Name this song, the third remix of which features the “yodeling kid” Mason Ramsey. A lyric about marijuana was deleted from this song before its artist’s first collaboration with Billy Ray Cyrus. ","answer":"ANSWER: “Old Town Road” "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"J","question":"[10] The fourth remix of “Old Town Road” features RM, a member of this K-pop group. Fans of this group nominated its members for the Nobel Peace Prize after this group began the Love Myself movement against domestic violence. ","answer":"ANSWER: BTS [or Bangtan Boys; or Bangtan Sonyeondan] (The remix is also referred to as “Seoul Town Road.”) "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"J","question":"9. In the video, music critic Anthony Fantano plays a guard of this location. ","answer":"ANSWER: Area 51 [or Homey Airport; or Groom Lake] <CE/Geo/Other/Pop Culture> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"J","question":"[10] Name this B minor symphony, numbered the eighth by its composer. Brian Newbould hypothesized that the entr’acte (“ON-tract”) from its composer’s incidental music to Rosamunde was created from the incomplete sketches of this piece’s closing scherzo. ","answer":"ANSWER: the Unfinished Symphony [or D. 759; accept, but DO NOT REVEAL, Franz Schubert’s Eighth Symphony in B minor, or Schubert’s Seventh Symphony in B minor] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"J","question":"[10] This classical-era composer’s Unfinished Symphony is sometimes labeled the first Romantic symphony. This proto-Romantic also wrote the liederkreis (“LEE-der-kryce”) Winterreise (“VIN-ter-RYE-zuh”). ","answer":"ANSWER: Franz Schubert "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"J","question":"[10] This proto-Romantic’s incidental music to Gozzi’s (“GOT-see’s”) Turandot (“TUR-in-dot”) is used in Hindemith’s (“HIN-duh-mit’s”) Symphonic Metamorphosis. Berlioz shoved this composer’s Invitation to the Dance into an opera in which Samiel (“ZOM-eel”) helps create magic bullets. ","answer":"ANSWER: Carl Maria von Weber (“VAY-bur”) (The opera is Der Freischütz.) <Classical Music> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"J","question":"[10] This compound with formula C3H6 is formed in the Simmons–Smith reaction. Its conformation is unstable due to the presence of banana bonds. ","answer":"ANSWER: cyclopropane "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"J","question":"[10] Cyclopropane is a cyclic example of this class of compounds because it is a saturated hydrocarbon. Methane is the simplest example of these compounds. ","answer":"ANSWER: alkane "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"J","question":"[10] This cyclic ether is often used as an industrial solvent for polyvinyl chloride. It is also a popular solvent for hydroboration reactions and for organolithium and Grignard (“green-YARR”) reagents. ","answer":"ANSWER: THF [or tetrahydrofuran] <Chemistry> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"J","question":"[10] Name this pleasant hallucinogenic drug. The World State uses this drug to control its population in Brave New World. ","answer":"ANSWER: soma "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"J","question":"[10] Brave New World is a novel by this author. This author described his own experience using the psychedelic drug mescaline in The Doors of Perception. ","answer":"ANSWER: Aldous Huxley "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"J","question":"[10] Slake Moths produce a hallucinogenic drug named for this word followed by “shit” in China Miéville’s (“mee-AY-vul’s”) Perdido Street Station. This word is the primary name of the protagonist of Neil Gaiman’s The Sandman. ","answer":"ANSWER: dream [accept dreamshit] <British Literature> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"J","question":"[10] Name this Spanish-American “liberator” who returned from exile to secure the independence of Gran Colombia. ","answer":"ANSWER: Simón Bolívar "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"J","question":"[10] Before returning to liberate Gran Colombia, Bolívar outlined his vision of a unified Latin America in this 1815 letter, named for the British colony he was living in. ","answer":"ANSWER: Letter from Jamaica [accept Jamaica letter or Carta de Jamaica] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"J","question":"[10] In 1819, Bolívar secured Colombian independence after crushing a Spanish army at this battle. Two years later, Bolívar followed up his victory at this battle by liberating his native Venezuela upon winning at Carabobo. ","answer":"ANSWER: Battle of Boyacá <World History> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"J","question":"[10] Name this philosopher whose magnum opus takes its structure from Euclid’s Elements and is thus subtitled Demonstrated in Geometrical Order. That book is his Ethics. ","answer":"ANSWER: Baruch Spinoza "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"J","question":"[10] Spinoza repeated the phrase “God or nature” four times in his Ethics because he believed in this doctrine. This belief conflates God with all things in the universe. ","answer":"ANSWER: pantheism [or word forms; or panentheism] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"J","question":"[10] This fourth of the five chapters of Spinoza’s Ethics begins by defining perfection, imperfection, good, and evil. Its argument that humans are slaves to their emotions is counteracted by the last chapter, which proposes intellect as a means for “Human Freedom.” ","answer":"ANSWER: “Of Human Bondage” [or “Of the Servitude of Humanity”; or “On Human Bondage”; or “De Servitute Humana”] <Philosophy> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"J","question":"[10] Name this specific community of early Christian ascetics. These practitioners of hesychasm (“HESS-ih-KAZ-um”), a form of silent, internal prayer, were named for their place of residence in the Wadi El Natrun. ","answer":"ANSWER: Desert Fathers "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"J","question":"[10] This Desert Father, the patron saint of skin diseases, successfully withstood numerous temptations during his journey into the desert. ","answer":"ANSWER: Saint Anthony the Great [or Anthony the Abbot, Anthony of the Desert, Anthony the Anchorite, and Anthony of Thebes; accept “The Temptation of St. Anthony”; accept, but DO NOT REVEAL, Anthony of Egypt; prompt on the Father of All Monks; do not accept or prompt on “Anthony of Padua” or “Anthony of Lisbon”] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"J","question":"[10] Anthony’s biographer Athanasius served as the bishop of Alexandria in this modern country, which also serves as the headquarters of the Coptic Church. ","answer":"ANSWER: Egypt [or the Arab Republic of Egypt] <Religion> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"J","question":"[10] Name this photographic journal published from 1903 to 1917 by Alfred Stieglitz, following his stint as editor of Camera Notes. This publication was the first to feature Stieglitz’s photo The Steerage. ","answer":"ANSWER: Camera Work "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"J","question":"[10] Stieglitz sought to raise photography to a fine art as a member of a group named for “Photo” and this word. Gustav Klimt was a leading member of an artistic movement in Vienna named for this word. ","answer":"ANSWER: secession [accept word forms like secessionism or secessionist; accept Photo-Secession; accept Vienna Secession] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"J","question":"[10] Stieglitz also prolifically photographed this woman. This painter’s close-up depictions of flowers have been interpreted as symbolizing female genitalia. ","answer":"ANSWER: Georgia O’Keeffe <Other Arts> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"J","question":"[10] Name this coefficient that is multiplied by surface area and temperature difference in a law of cooling. It can be used to describe convective conditions at a solid–fluid interface. ","answer":"ANSWER: heat transfer coefficient [accept film coefficient; prompt on h] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"J","question":"[10] That law of cooling is named for this English scientist, whose other achievements in physics include formulating a universal law of gravitation and three laws of motion. ","answer":"ANSWER: Isaac Newton "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"J","question":"[10] Conductive heat flow is modeled by this law that, for one dimension, states that heat flux through a surface is equal to negative one times conductivity times the derivative of temperature at that surface. ","answer":"ANSWER: Fourier’s law <Physics> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"J","question":"[10] Name this position. Its only legitimate holder underwent 55 assassination attempts motivated by blood feuds, including one in which he returned with his own pistol after an attempt on his life at a showing of Pagliacci. ","answer":"ANSWER: king of Albania [prompt on ruler of Albania; do not accept or prompt on “president of Albania” or “prime minister of Albania”] (The king is Zog I.) "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"J","question":"[10] The great king Zog was forced to abdicate after the invasion of Albania by this World War II–era Italian fascist known as Il Duce (“DOO-chay”). ","answer":"ANSWER: Benito Mussolini [or Benito Amilcare Andrea Mussolini] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"J","question":"[10] Zog’s effective successor was the communist Enver Hoxha (“HO-juh”), who built 170,000 of these structures throughout Albania. Devices known as “busters” of these structures are designed to penetrate into the ground before detonation. ","answer":"ANSWER: concrete bunkers [accept nuclear bunkers; accept bunkerët; prompt on fortifications or bomb shelters; prompt on pillboxes] <European History> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"J","question":"[10] Name this 1956 book by C. Wright Mills, sometimes considered a counterpart to White Collar. It claims that the average citizen is powerless against the title conglomeration of political, military, and business leaders. ","answer":"ANSWER: The Power Elite "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"J","question":"[10] Robert Dahl wrote Who Governs? in part as a rebuttal to The Power Elite; for it, Dahl studied the polyarchic government of the surrounding town of New Haven while working at this Ivy League university in Connecticut. ","answer":"ANSWER: Yale University "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"J","question":"[10] The emphasis on bureaucracy in The Power Elite parallels this earlier book, which contrasts a “light cloak” and “shell as hard as steel” to discuss one of many modern socioeconomic consequences of northern European Calvinism. ","answer":"ANSWER: The Protestant Ethic and the Spirit of Capitalism [or Die protestantische Ethik und der Geist des Kapitalismus] (by Max Weber) <Social Science> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"J","question":"[10] Name this author, who described the title character’s love for the castrato Zambinella in Sarrasine. Raphael de Valentin is given a magic skin that shrinks as it grants his wishes in this author’s The Wild Ass’s Skin. ","answer":"ANSWER: Honoré de Balzac "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"J","question":"[10] Sarrasine and The Wild Ass’s Skin are grouped alongside Eugénie Grandet (“oo-zhay-NEE gron-DAY”) and Le Père Goriot (“luh pair gor-YO”) in this large collection of novels by Balzac. Its title references an epic by Dante. ","answer":"ANSWER: The Human Comedy [or La Comédie humaine] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"J","question":"[10] Barthes discusses a line from Sarrasine to begin this essay, which argues that the author’s intention should not be given special preference when analyzing a text. This essay concludes by stating that “the birth of the reader must be ransomed” by the title event. ","answer":"ANSWER: “The Death of the Author” [or Le morte d’auteur] <European Literature>"}]
